<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>弘毅阁 • Posts by &#34;travel&#34; tag</title>
        <link>http://example.com</link>
        <description>A place to record fruit of life.</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 19:04:45 +0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 19:04:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <category>thought</category>
        <category>PhD</category>
        <category>work</category>
        <category>travel</category>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">http://example.com/2024/08/31/Mojito-Cigar-and-Salsa/</guid>
            <title>Mojito,Cigar and Salsa</title>
            <link>http://example.com/2024/08/31/Mojito-Cigar-and-Salsa/</link>
            <category>travel</category>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 19:04:45 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;7&amp;#x2F;28-8&amp;#x2F;15&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; If you ask me to recommend only one place for traveling, Cuba will be my answer for sure! For me, it left me with impressive and unreplaceable memory. From general perspective, as a county of total Socialism, life in Cuba seems as mysterious as North Korea, apart from the enthusiastic vibe and impressive beaches and forests. One thing to complain will be its high temperature all year round. There are three things to represent Cuba, which are mojito, cigar and salsa. Drink a shot of mojito, take a cigar, and dance a salsa. What a life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; As a Chinese guy, I am familiar with Socialism for sure. But as I grew up, my society has been reformed already since the 1980s. As a Gen Z, marketing in China has not been restricted any more. We called “two hands” controlling the economy, the government and market. From my view, it is kind of similar with the New Deal by Roosevelt. Government places an important role in promoting big programs such as transportation engineering, and lets the market optimize the economy, but this process is detected by government for macro-control. However, Cuba is different because it is more like Chine without economy reform. I was curious about people’s life there, especially in post-pandemic era. Also, the history and its culture were attractive for me.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The following was the notes I took during travel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;关于古巴美好的人间烟火&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;作为游客停留在古巴三个星期，古巴给我留下的印象是热情的音乐、适量的满足和悠然的生活。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;无论在哪个城市哪个角落，音乐永远是古巴人民表达对生活热爱的方式。城市的中央广场是人们娱乐的集散地，当气温下降，孩童与大人们在这里载歌载舞抑或谈论着一天的生活。印象最深的是在Santa Clara的一个餐馆，客人会饶有兴致地加入歌唱表演，街边也会组织音乐与表演。人们脱离电子设备的束缚在音乐中拥抱现实的生活。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;同时，生活也是适当的满足。政府给予每人每月一斤米一斤肉六斤豆（依城市而定）剩余的食物水果则在市场上购买，看病有免费的医疗。看起来人们不会为了赚钱而消耗自己的精力，不会为金钱而丢失自己的生活，似乎知足常乐。而我们的生活呢？谁未曾幻想着35岁退休享受生活，却在35岁时生活在自己构筑的房子、车子、度假的高墙中。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;最后，生活的节奏在这里仿佛慢了一拍。随处可见的六十年代的车子好似走入电影一般。人们慢慢悠悠地在街上行走，就连猫狗都慵懒地躺在地上。一切关于时间的记忆都停滞了，加之全年炽热的温度，仿佛忘记了今夕何夕，今天的一切与昨日的一切没有任何变化。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;关于古巴美好背后的现实&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;作为独自旅行的背包客，其中的乐趣就在于与人交流，在不同城市与民宿老板聊、与同行的旅客聊、与本地的街溜子聊。上一篇记录了古巴的美好，这一篇就片面地记录下我所了解到的现实的古巴生活。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;作为社会主义，市场经济在古巴寸步难行，但如果政府没有工作机会了呢？想象一下九十年代下岗后却无法从事个体经济，这就是古巴的现状。在古巴你会发现虽然四面环海，却没人垂钓，为何？因为违法！普通人很难有资格钓鱼，同样其他的个体经济如果没有购买许可证都是违法（抓到两年起步）那如何购买许可证？用美元或欧元！这就是为何人们在黑市上换钱，然而汇率变化得可怕（3月份1美元换150，8月份1美元换250）那没有钱又没有工作怎么办？黑市街边的生意成为他们最后的生存方式。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;那在古巴的工资如何呢？政府最低工资2k比索，护士8k比索，警察10k比索。这么看可能没有概念，我来举个例子在哈瓦那我一顿饭就会吃掉2k+比索，一升牛奶2k比索。在这里牛奶成为了奢侈品。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;那离开古巴呢？困难至极。首先护照、签证等一系列的成本极高，只有少数家庭有能力送孩子出国。但去年也有近百万年轻人离开古巴，其中也包含走线的(tb)。有的人划着小船去福罗里达，有的人在墨西哥徒步戈壁，当然一个大浪或者大漠孤烟就会让人永远沉眠。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;在古巴，城市或许是最糟糕的地方，就像温铁军先生说的，城市的人失去了土地的后盾。十年前来过古巴的越南老哥跟我说哈瓦那在沉沦，贫困、能源紧缺、食品水紧缺、衣服紧缺、医疗资源紧缺。村落和小镇的人们或许是幸福的，因为食物能够自给自足，对于精神的追求也可以通过烟酒与音乐来满足。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;记忆最深的是在哈瓦那街头与我攀谈的失业大叔。几个月前工厂关闭，没有了任何经济来源，皮肤由于快速消瘦叠了好几层皮，但自己还有两个孩子要养。他与我谈起中国建方舱医院只用了两周，眼神中露出了敬佩的目光。我刚想说这是靠人们夜以继日的加班来实现的，而年轻人更想要朝九晚五的工作，但看到他的目光我把话吞了回去。或许对于他而言，工作就是一种莫大的幸福了，而我们或许在追求不同的目标。与他聊了一个下午，他哽咽我无奈，最后给了他1k比索我买下了他的故事。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;所以，这看起来安逸的生活是我们追求的吗？作为旅人，我还是很喜欢古巴，这里安逸的生活、热情的人们、停滞的时间，或许仅仅停留在旅行的层面。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the English translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;On the Beautiful Aspects of Cuba’s Everyday Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; As a tourist staying in Cuba for three weeks, the impression Cuba left on me was one of passionate music, modest satisfaction, and a leisurely lifestyle.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; In every city and corner, music is always the way the Cuban people express their love for life. The central square of a city is a hub of entertainment. When the temperature drops, children and adults gather there to sing, dance, or talk about their day. What impressed me the most was a restaurant in Santa Clara, where guests enthusiastically joined in the singing performances, and music and performances were organized on the street. People, free from the constraints of electronic devices, embraced real life through music.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; At the same time, life is also about appropriate contentment. The government provides each person with one jin (half a kilogram) of rice, one jin of meat, and six jin of beans (depending on the city) per month. The rest of the food and fruit is bought at the market. Medical care is free. It seems that people do not exhaust themselves trying to earn money and do not lose their lives for the sake of money; they appear to be content with what they have. And what about our lives? Who hasn’t fantasized about retiring at 35 to enjoy life, but at 35, we find ourselves trapped in the high walls of the houses, cars, and vacations we’ve built.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Lastly, life here seems to slow down a beat. The sight of cars from the sixties makes you feel like you’ve stepped into a movie. People stroll leisurely on the streets, and even the cats and dogs lazily lie on the ground. All memories of time seem to have stopped. Combined with the scorching temperatures all year round, it feels as if people have forgotten what day it is; today is no different from yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;On the Reality Behind Cuba’s Beauty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; As a solo backpacker, the fun lies in communicating with people, chatting with guesthouse owners in different cities, fellow travelers, or local street dwellers. The last article recorded the beauty of Cuba; this one will one-sidedly document the reality of Cuban life as I understand it.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; As a socialist country, market economy struggles in Cuba. But what if the government doesn’t have job opportunities? Imagine being laid off in the 90s without being able to engage in private business; that’s the current situation in Cuba. In Cuba, you’ll find that although it is surrounded by the sea, no one fishes. Why? Because it’s illegal! Ordinary people have little chance to fish. Similarly, other private businesses are illegal without a permit (which comes with at least a two-year sentence if caught). And how do you get a permit? With dollars or euros! That’s why people exchange money on the black market, but the exchange rates fluctuate terrifyingly (from 150 pesos for 1 dollar in March to 250 pesos in August). So, what do you do if you have no money and no job? Street business on the black market becomes their last means of survival.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; What about wages in Cuba? The minimum government salary is 2,000 pesos, 8,000 pesos for nurses, and 10,000 pesos for police officers. These figures might seem abstract, so let me give you an example: in Havana, I could spend over 2,000 pesos on just one meal; a liter of milk costs 2,000 pesos. Milk has become a luxury here.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; And what about leaving Cuba? It’s extremely difficult. The costs of passports, visas, and other paperwork are prohibitively high, and only a few families can afford to send their children abroad. Still, nearly a million young people left Cuba last year, some of whom took dangerous routes (tb). Some rowed small boats to Florida, and others trekked across the deserts of Mexico. But, of course, a big wave or a desert storm could result in eternal sleep.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; In Cuba, cities may be the worst places, as Mr. Wen Tiejun said, city dwellers have lost the backing of the land. A Vietnamese friend who visited Cuba ten years ago told me that Havana is sinking into poverty, with shortages of energy, food, water, clothes, and medical resources. Villagers and small-town residents might be happier because they can be self-sufficient in food and find spiritual satisfaction in tobacco, alcohol, and music.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; What I remember most is a conversation with an unemployed uncle on the streets of Havana. A few months ago, his factory closed, leaving him without any income. His skin sagged from rapid weight loss, yet he still had two children to support. He spoke admiringly of China’s ability to build a makeshift hospital in two weeks. I was about to say that this was achieved through people’s around-the-clock overtime, while young people would rather have a nine-to-five job. But seeing the look in his eyes, I swallowed my words. Perhaps, for him, having a job is a great blessing, while we might be pursuing different goals. We talked for an afternoon; he choked up, and I was helpless. In the end, I gave him 1,000 pesos and bought his story.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; So, is this seemingly leisurely life what we are after? As a traveler, I still love Cuba, with its easy-going life, warm people, and time standing still, but maybe only on the level of a travel experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">http://example.com/2024/08/29/beeilen/</guid>
            <title>Langsam Beeilen</title>
            <link>http://example.com/2024/08/29/beeilen/</link>
            <category>travel</category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 16:14:47 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The title is a German slang, which means “slowly hurry&amp;#x2F;go”. I learned this slang from a German friend, Franz, during volunteering. I really love this slang. People always expect preparing everything before conducting a plan, while it will never be perfect, which will slow down your pace to move on. “Slowly hurry&amp;#x2F;go” depicts a status of moving on a little bit without perfect preparation.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Similarly, my travel is not perfectly prepared, but once I put myself on the way traveling, I knew I made it. My first stop was Atlanta and Miami. Carrying on over 60lb bagages, I flew from Chicago to Atlanta to visit uncle Frank who was my dad’s classmate living in Atlanta. I stayed at his home for a week. We went fishing, worked out, and shot guns. Everything I experienced there was so American style. That was my first fishing experience. The fish guide detected groups of fish by rada and sonar. We finally got more than ten weevers. They are kind of delicious but not easy to cook. The last but not the least, we enjoyed Chinese food! It was hard to express how much I missed those food. While, time flew quickly, and I went to Miami to catch my flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; In Miami, I met my friends and traveled around as well. One of my best friend, Cong, came from Boston to farewell. She brought me some stuff that I would use during my travel. Also, she was a lecturer in MIT. I really respected her a lot, and we also discussed some details of writing an academic paper. Sure! I did some academic research while traveling. Another friend was a classmate working in a landscape architecture corp. He complained a lot to me about his boss and his working schedule, over ten hours a day! I had to say international students sometimes were disadvantaged group in the labor market. I also met a family from Britain, my host family. The host was Canadian, and his wife was Cuban. They had a son named Lin. Interestingly, Lin is a typical Chinese last name. The hostess told me she loved Chinese name. When I told her my next spot was Cuba. She was superised and made some phone call to her family in Cuba to inform me the latest condition in Cuba. She said it was not perfect to travel at that moment because of poor economy. I was scared a little bit but still wanted to observe by myself. So, I shared my number with her and updated my travel then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; On July 28th, 2023, I left for Cuba, a mysterious country in my “world”.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">http://example.com/2024/08/15/Advanture/</guid>
            <title>New Advanture</title>
            <link>http://example.com/2024/08/15/Advanture/</link>
            <category>travel</category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 14:53:16 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; “Travel around the world” is the most romantic experience that I could imagine in my life. It’s been a while since I completed my world travel in 2023. Whenever I recall this amazing experience, I always feel excited and unforgetable. Now, I think it is a good point to record my experience as my memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Exploration has been the rhythm of my life since I was a kid. My home was moved to different places for multiple times, which enforced me to get familiar with new environment frequently. From a countryside to a small town, from the City of Harbin to Shanghai, a new environment broaden my view and reconstructed my attitude of life. Interestingly, I was a timid boy before middle school. It’s funny to recall my childhood that I could barely go to a library alone which was only 2 kilometer away from my home. To be brave enough, I always went to school as a group with my best friends. I guess that might be caused by frequent changes of living environment. I got easily surprised at unfamiliar stuff. Meanwhile, even if I was too timid to travel alone, I tried my best to hang out with my friends and my family at different places. A huge change happened when I completed my primary school in Harbin. My family moved to Shanghai, an international mega city, not similar with Harbin anymore. The living environment changed again, but this time was a little different. Summer is hotter with higher humity in Shanghai, and people’s accent is different. My old friends were 2,000 kilometers away from me. I had to make new friends, learn new accent, and get used to a more complex environment than before. Fortunately, I enjoyed this change. My parents were busy with work, and I made new friends alone. Also, I got brave enough to travel by myself. Sometimes, I could get some budget from parents to support my trips. My home was moved twice more inside the city until I finished my high school in 2015. I went college in Beijing. Actually, I did not apply any colleges in Shanghai because this time I wanted to explore “ouside” alone. I was not static during undergraduate, and I traveled to most provinces in China. I also learned a lot outside textbook, from travel and work in the Red Cross. Then, I applied UIUC for my Masters’ Degrees. In terms of my expertise, I broaded my knowledge from civil engineering to urban plannning to geography. I enjoyed merging my knowledge and utilized my advange to guide new field, such as use data analysis in policy and decision making. When completed my degrees. I enrolled in a post-graduate program, which allowed me to work in the government of Illinois, and make enough money for travelling. At the age of 25, I got a perfect condition with good “health”, flexable “schedule”, and enough “budget”. Even I could have applied a higher-salary job, but I still decided to explore the world first and learn from the “outside”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; On July 18th, as the horn of Amtrak coming close to me at Springfield train station, I carried on my bags and started my expected new advanture of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
